Um.
Welcome back.
Let's go ahead and continue on with this
exercise. So.
If you could raise your hands so that I
can see when we're when you're getting
when you're finished with this exercise.
What we're trying to do here is to
continue our process of increasing our
test automation.
OK.
So we're continuing on this exercise,
so raise your hands if you're if you
haven't completed this exercise yet.
And if you have a question,
just shout it out.
Raise your hand if you were completed or
not completed.
Not completed.
John.
Yes.
Is it possible you can post some example
prompts for these activity items?
Because otherwise I feel like I'm just
typing exactly what I see. For example,
Sure.
run linting and architectural checks.
That's literally what I would write into
Yeah.
the prompt.
Unless there's a better way to do it.
Um.
Yeah, well, I mean you could say,
you know, you could, you could, well,
let me,
I'll type in and I'll change over to it.
But the idea would be that you're you'll
be asking for the architectural alignment,
you know, review the the code base.
For the conformance to the architectural
standards for the project, right?
Or look for deviations between the
architecture or weaknesses with the
architecture or how the architecture
could be improved things as.
Jobs like that would be how I would go
about that. And in terms of linting,
you're you're basically asking it to
identify, you know, a good one would be,
you know,
review the code base and identify any bad
smells.
So that would be one way of accomplishing
that because I mean we don't want to.
Implement in a I something that that's
already well established in other tools
like you know like a linter.
So we want to we want to try to target
analysis of the code base that's.
That goes beyond what the linting this,
you know, the static linting tools can do.
OK. Yeah. Just my general comment was I'm,
I'm not really an expert on the prompting
side of things.
So any kind of guidance would be helpful.
Sure.
Thanks.
Anybody's can you update your?
You raised hands, so if you finish this.
Yeah,
it made ETETE and integration tests as
well for me just in the one unit test
project.
You know it's put up its own web server
and it's using like in memory databases
None.
and things like that, so.
I was gonna look and see how the speed is
if that's slow,
like whether that's something we'd want
to run, you know,
on every commit or that would be
something that we want to do maybe just
like once a day or something like this.
Right, if it's fast, you could do this,
you know, before allowing a a a commit.
If it's slower,
you would maybe do this on a merge to the
main branch.
And yeah, and added as a.
Like a a part of your get up actions or
your or any of the the kind of triggers
that you can capture in in your whatever.
Source control system that you're working
with.
Yeah.
All right, and we about ready to move on.
What I want to show is.
What I've done here in in terms of.
In terms of, you know,
examining that code base.
I I did a fairly simple prompt.
I'll put this in the chat.
Yeah, I see that, Steve. And that's not.
I've also seen it where.
It'll it at least in the past haven't
seen it recently where would they say
that well somebody has modified this file
and therefore it's it's been corrupted
and I need to recreate it when nobody,
when actually nobody has actually made
the change,
it just somehow loses the context.
That could be a context window problem as
well.
Um.
Right. So it's, you know,
it's sometimes just really you need need
a little bit of lecture guidance or you
need to point it to something or ask it a
question that will help it, you know.
That'll help direct it towards a a a a
proper solution.
So I ran this prompt which is.
In the workspace review report any bad
smells and what I thought is interesting
about this is that.
I didn't define what bad smells were.
And so basically again relying on
inference.
It was able to essentially come up with
these smells.
Some of this is redundant with some of
the other prompts that and other findings
that we've got from other prompts,
but it's looking for security issues.
Code duplication.
Some some naming problems.
Missing validation, architectural issues,
business logic issues and error handling
testing problems.
Performance and data integrity. So,
so this is again just another way that we
can ask AI to examine that code base for
things that might need to be addressed
and have it.
You know,
go ahead and identify those those areas.
And here I've got to create files that
describe each issue in a way that we
could actually have them posted to GitHub
and.
Or whatever issue of tracking system that
you're using and get and then get that
onto onto the.
Onto the plate of things that we actually
want to try to address.
Uh.
Any questions on this exercise and what
we've done here?
All right then.
Let's go ahead and move on to Um.
The next area.
Um.
Sorry about that.
I'm just having a little issue with
resuming the PowerPoint presentation, so.
Mhm.
Let me get it started.
There we go.
All right, so.
Let's talk just a bit about testing
frameworks.
So here we've talked talking about
comprehensive test weeks,
dealing with test weeks over time,
test review and validation strategies,
balancing test coverage with
maintainability and.
Right.
So some key practices by managing tests
over time is that we want to regularly
prune obsolete tests.
So if we have tests that are testing old
functionality or the like,
we want to get those out of the code base.
We really want to try to update those
tests alongside the code changes and you
know,
preferably actually write tests for new
code or update those tests when we want
to make changes so that the test we can
use a more of a test driven development
approach.
And since we have AI as a to help us
write test,
it's you know test driven development is
a lot more a lot easier to to achieve
because you can actually ask AI to write
the test and then have it.
And then you can actually go and make
sure that the implementation matches or
or or cause the test to pass.
You want clear naming and a clear
structure of your test.
You want to use those code cover reports
to to guide where you need to actually
make changes.
And when you're creating a a test
strategy document or an implementation
document,
make that part of the the code base as
well.
For reviewing tests and validation,
we can get the AI assistant that can
detect any mission assertions,
redundant tests,
edge cases and flag any inconsistent
patterns.
And when we're when we're looking at
tests, we want to,
we want to make sure that.
That the test encapsulates the the the
intent of the code so that we're we're
validating what we expect it to do and
not validating what it does.
We certainly want to focus on business
logic validation and architectural
alignment as being one of our main
concerns.
Going forward and and I I mentioned a day
or so ago that from my perspective as a
as an architect and somebody who is
interested in the the project as a whole,
I'm very interested in making sure that
the the test.
Suite that I'm building gives me the
confidence that I can make the changes.
I'm not as concerned at the
implementation and you can make an
argument that if the code is primarily
being written by a I.
That the the implementation,
if it conforms to the instructions that
we provide,
is going to be pretty close to what we
would expect if we were to write it by
hand.
And so we should be able to to see decent,
decent code generation coming out of AI
that we wouldn't.
Have to make a whole lot of changes to
because if we found that we needed to
Um.
make code changes,
we would want to go back and update our
instructions to make sure that those get
flagged and don't get implemented again.
Questions. Yeah, Lyle.
All right, moving forward then.
Sorry about that. I hit that accident.
Well, no worries.
Well.
Yeah, I just had a comment about,
you know,
unit tests and AI generated unit tests.
I find that it just creates way too much,
Yeah.
you know,
it's just it creates way too many tests.
I I also always have to tell it to like
scale it back. Otherwise I'll have like,
you know, 10 tests for a.
1010 line method with 10 lines of code.
So I'm wondering you know is that?
I mean, have you seen that too?
The the unit tests are also overly
But.
verbose and overly too much stuff.
Yeah,
I think that at times I I think if you,
you know,
create an instruction file that helps it
understand what your expectations are in
terms of tests, you know, some sort of,
you know,
some sort of value guidance that would
tell it,
you know how much value this particular
test has.
In terms of in terms of what code is
actually testing,
you know like that that can that can help
fine tune that test suite so that it's
has a a larger impact.
So that would be something I would be
looking to do if I started to notice that
that the test.
Sweet was getting too big.
Yeah.
And the other thing that you can that
just I'm thinking that you can do is
going forward is that when you need to
make a modification,
you can ask AI to identify the tests that
need to be updated in order to make that
particular change in the code and that
way you can focus the AI on.
Updating and modifying the tests that are
applicable and in that way, if you have a,
even if you have a lot of tests,
you can get,
you can keep those tests up to date,
up to date with the code base and make
sure that it's accurate.
And it's not testing things that
shouldn't be tested.
We talked about suggesting edge cases.
We want to make sure that we're we're
seeing in the code in the test suite that
we're we're we're seeing a sad path test
as well as our happy path tests.
And again,
we're looking for validating intents.
I had a question on on this a bit more.
So let's say you make a code change to
the architecture or like add a feature.
How do you know if the AI is?
Correcting the unit test to comply to the
new feature,
or if it's actually catching a real
mistake due to the inclusion of the new
code.
You're saying a a a mistake in the test
or a mistake or a mistake in the.
Yeah. How, how, how,
how confident are you in AI making the
right decision there for?
Yeah, that's, you know,
we kind of showed it that a little bit
yesterday where we selected and tested.
We had,
we had the AI explain what that test did,
right. And again,
this is a useful exercise to.
Try a a model that didn't create the code
that so that you kind of try to eliminate
the some bias in that response.
But the idea would be you can have that a
I examine that that test to make sure
that it's accurate and you can accurately
explain the test to see if you if it
makes sense to you.
And I think that that those kinds of
strategies or techniques will help you
raise the the confidence that you have in
that particular test you know and then
you could or and you can also take a test
driven approach before you make the
OK.
change at all.
Say I need a way to modify this test.
Test to test for this change in the
functionality of the application and then
those tests will then start to fail
because the new implementation isn't
there and then you can then ask it to
implement the functionality so that the
test passes.
And I think that's a also a good way to
verify that that the tests are actually
doing what you're expected to do.
OK. Thanks.
Other question.
Moving on.
OK, so um.
Let's start now moving towards how we're
going to do some coding.
So we want to do some things here that we
in order for us to be comfortable
actually starting to make these changes.
We talked about feature flags in the past
to minimize risk.
You can write some some queries to help
us do that.
I want to talk about as is and to be test
suites as a a technique for making sure
that our our our that we're able to go to
production at any moment and.
And that we have good tests around the
new code that's going in in and how to
manage that.
We'll talk about testing in production
and retiring some retiring feature flags.
So feature flags, why they matter,
but they do a lot of things they enable.
In my mind,
a lot of capabilities on the release side
of things that can really add a lot of
value.
So you can do things like enable an
incremental roll out,
which is what I mentioned before where
you start with a small group of users and
then slowly incrementally.
Roll the feature out while you're
monitoring the system for failures and if
you see anything that's a problem,
you can just roll back or change the
state of the feature flag and
automatically roll back that feature so
that.
It's not affecting users experiences.
This allows you to also reduce the blast
radius by not rolling out a feature to
the entire organization.
You're reducing the potential for
problems and the risk of that rollout as
well as you can.
Use those feature flags to to hide code
that isn't actually ready to to for users
to see.
You can do AB testing and do do what's
called shadow traffic.
AB testing would be that I implement the
a feature maybe two different ways.
And so half the users one way and half
the users the other and then monitor for
what their experience is and and then
essentially roll out either the ARM
version.
A shadow traffic is a nice technique
where you can take a.
A piece of code and you can direct
traffic to both implementations and
verify that the the new implementation
performs as well as the old
implementation does and or and make a and
then it that it functions properly and
doesn't generate a lot of errors.
And this could be before anybody actually
sees the activity.
It just happens behind the scenes and it
helps you decouple deployment from
release,
which means that you can have a set of
feature flags that are off in production
but on.
In your development environment and by
and which allows you effectively to
continue to roll out new code changes
with the comfort that that the things
that you don't want the users to see are
hidden.
And then whenever you feel comfortable
with that new feature,
you can turn the toggle on and you don't
need to do a deployment in order to
release the feature to the users.
This allows you to deploy many times,
but only release when you're when you
have confidence.
Some practices you want to keep the the
feature flags as short lived as you can,
so it's really wrapped around a feature
and it only exists for the length of time
it takes for you to get that feature
deployed to all to your entire user base
and then you can remove it.
You want them to have a follow a naming
convention that allows you to easily
identify what they're for,
and you want to document what the intent
was and what the retirement criteria is
so that you can go back and you know and
remove the and remove the.
The the the feature flag and any old code
that might be associated that might not
be executed anymore because of that
feature flag is is permanently on or that
code is now permanently permanently a
part of the code code base.
Any future comments on feature flags?
Anybody use them in in your applications?
Yeah, we actually use them quite a bit.
Even before AI, we've been using them for,
you know, five plus years.
Right? Yeah.
Thank.
Go ahead.
Just agreed, same.
OK, great.
Um.
And then, yeah, Chris.
We develop heavily.
Our product is heavily Power Platform,
so a lot of plugins through Power
Platform and solutions and I've been
looking at feature flags as an option for
us, but I'm.
I haven't seen any examples of it used in
that development stack.
OK.
I was wondering if anyone has any
experience around that.
Um.
Without knowing a lot about it,
I would think that if you have the
ability to to call out to an external
component that can manage the flags for
you and branch based upon that component.
Return values and that might be a
strategy that would work, but.
I don't know for sure.
So any other questions?
Right.
So retirement of flags you want.
You don't want flag bloat and you don't
want code that's in your code base that's
no longer gonna be executed because a
flag has been changed.
So you want to basically retire all of
that code.
This will reduce the cognitive load and
the complexity of the implementation
because you're simplifying the code paths
and it makes a more a long-term makes
makes it more maintainable long-term.
So the retirement workflow is you.
Once you reach a stable point where
everybody has the the feature flag
enabled and it appears to be working fine,
you remove the old code pass,
you update the documentation and add the
the provenance to that change so that
you've recorded that modification and in.
You know you can use AI and one of the
techniques that I had used in the past
before AI was this was to actually create
a.
A pull request when I implemented the.
The feature flag that I where I can merge
that Pearl request in and at some later
date and then retire the flag that way
and some success with that.
But you can also just then with AI just
say I want to identify.
You know the changes that I need to make
in order to move this feature flag and it
it it would be it would be effective at
easily removing that feature flag from
the code base. Questions here.
All right,
so let's talk about as is in in 2B test
suites.
This is and the idea here is that you
have a a a suite of tests which are the
as is tests which capture the current
behavior. As I as I mentioned,
it doesn't necessarily have to be
comprehensive, but what tests you do have.
You trust and and they they verify the
behaviour that you actually have for
testing purposes.
And I would increase or grow that as is
test suite as I identify changes that
need to be made to the code base and
write the as is test before I would make
any modifications to the code.
And then you have a this basically
protects you against regressions and and
and documents what your expectations are
for going to production.
So the idea would be is that you can go
to production anytime all the as is test
pass.
You don't care about the new
implementations,
they will be hidden behind feature flags
that cause keep the application from
executing.
So as long as the code base compiles
successfully,
you can do and the test as this test
passed.
You can have a a high level of confidence
that you're not introducing something
that would cause a problem.
What you do want to look for when you're
running these tests though,
is you want to make sure that the the
feature flags that you're implementing
don't bleed into production, right?
So you have to be careful that.
That that to be that the to be test that
you've actually in in effect what you're
looking for is any code that you've
implemented that's not wrapped by a
feature test that's going to show up in
the in production when you do it at.
When you do a deployment,
so the two B test suite defines that
future behaviour.
So you're you're basically you know the
the the workflow would be you would
implement a a feature flag around the
code that you want to modify and then
implement when it's flag is on.
You want to?
Execute the new behaviour and you want to
have a test around that new behaviour
that would only run when the feature flag
is on.
So you so the idea would be if you were
had had a test suite and were using
automation in your pipeline,
you would first set your flags in a state
that.
Is the same as what you have in
production.
You run all your current behaviour tests
and look for regressions.
Then you would run all the 2B tests with
the the appropriate flags turned on and
that would then execute those.
To be testing and give you a sense of how
you're doing in terms of being able to
finish the the work that's in progress.
And this is also useful in that you can
use these two bit Dooby tests,
which should be a much smaller.
Test suite than the as this test as a
part of your your check in procedure.
So if you're checking in a piece of code,
you want to make sure that the associated
2B tests are executed.
This helps you, you know,
as a guide to your modernization and how
to validate those new practices and
architectures that you might be putting
into place.
And the the one piece of maintenance that
you have to consider is that after you've
turned on that feature flag.
For that feature in production,
you need to move the tests that are
associated with that feature into the as
is test suite because it's now in
production and it needs to be part of the
regression suite.
Is it? Does that make sense?
Now testing and production,
you know this is well,
in many applications it's exactly what
you do is you got to test everything in
production.
But we want to do this in a more
engineered approach,
which means that we want that all that
feature flag.
Feature flags so it's hidden from users
until until it's actually ready.
This before you could use your shadow
traffic techniques and your Canary
releases.
You could have observability dashboards
that can report about issues that are
being raised and you can actually.
You can even automatically flip features
flags off if it observes that the that
the application is generating errors at
at at at an excessive rate.
So you can set a budget that says if you
see more errors than than a certain
number in a certain amount of time for
this particular feature,
you want to basically turn that that that
feature off and then notify you know the
powers that be that.
That you need to take a look at this
particular feature because it's it's not
functioning properly in in the production
world. So this gives us some.
So the in terms of testing in production,
the way I the way I've done this is that.
You essentially have a a a pool of users
that are internal users or beta testers
or whatever you like that you can then
say as a group say I want to enable this
particular feature for.
Just this group of people and therefore
there they can see this feature in in the
in the production environment.
They can test it in the production
environment and and and vet it out and
verify that in production it meets their
expectations and that can help you.
Make a determination of whether you need
more,
need to do more work or whether you you
can actually move this closer to a
production rollout.
So this gives you some real world
validation in a in a real environment
with real loads being put put on the
application at the at the time it can
give you some early detection of of Ed
cases that you might not have considered
because of.
When people actually touch it and try to
do things with it,
they might do things that you don't
expect,
and it reduces that risk of a full-scale
feature,
full-scale failure of that feature when
you actually roll it into production.
Any questions on this test testing in
production? Anybody doing this right now?
Buddy, is that something you do?
Dan, you had a comment?
Well, yeah, you know, I'm just wondering,
I think with feature flags,
like can it get quite complicated and
almost impossible like if we need to
update like database schema?
And you know,
just all the different dependencies like
doesn't that can can it get quite
complicated and almost like impractical
for some features?
My thinking for at first would be one I I
would for in terms of database schema
modifications,
I tend to take an approach that says that
modifications are additive, right?
So you would.
Add and it.
Let's just say that if you wanted to
retire a field,
you would add or replace it or just make
a simple one or just rename a column.
I would add the new column and I would
then.
Copy the information into the new column
that you would need,
and then make the modifications to the
code to use the new column.
And then once you're confident that
you're not using that new column,
I would retire it.
And so you can use a technique like that
where you're gradually moving your schema
forward, but you're adding things.
In production,
well before you actually decide to take
anything out,
and that gives you some confidence that
you're able to move forward efficiently
and effectively, yeah.
Oh.
I would say one benefit of doing it this
way that the reason why we do it a lot of
times is because if you're developing
like a very large feature that's going to
take months and you want, you want,
you don't want it to go stale, you know,
so like basically if you're.
Constantly rolling it out on every
release, but it's buying a feature flag.
You could catch those migration problems
and usually it would make the original
code base like if you really really need
to change the schema,
just go ahead and do it on both and that
way you know for sure that.
It's gonna be backwards compatible and
then and and you get that database clean
up.
But the the main thing that's a very a a
benefit with big teams or even a even
small teams and you're you know you're
you're all each doing different features
and stuff.
Is that if it's constantly rolling out
but it's behind feature flags you you'll
catch it in QA and and and hopefully you
don't catch it in production.
But you know like basically the the more
that you integrate,
you know have that integration point you
know with all your branches.
And have it roll out. It's just there.
It's just less surface area I guess you
could say on every release to worry about.
Right. Yeah,
that was mentioned a few slides ago about
reducing, reducing the blast radius,
right.
Yeah.
So you're if you're constantly rolling
into production with a small set of
changes, if something goes wrong,
you know what went wrong.
Whereas if you're working on a feature on
a feature branch and it takes you two
months to finish that feature,
getting that integrated into the rest of
the code base and out into production is
going to be a challenge, right?
It's from a both a testing perspective
and just to just making sure that you got
a solid merge going in and that's one
thing I.
I really try to avoid as much as I can is
work as closely to the the main trunk as
I can, which means keeping your branches.
Any branch that you take for any
particular purpose gets merged back into
the main code base as soon as possible.
And if you put it in a feature flag under
a feature flag,
that means you can do this almost
immediately and integrate it into the the
main code base and then and then easily
deploy that into production and get it
out there and integrate it with the rest
of the code base.
And if you've got a larger team where
you've got a lot of change,
a lot of churn in the code base,
it's even more, I think,
more important to get that code merged
early rather than waiting for it to be
ready before you actually push it out
into production and get it integrated
with the code base.
All right. Questions on this.
Other comments. Good.
Alright, so we talked a lot about that.
Um.
About the the code gaps.
So let's talk about like a remediation
plan for our our test suites.
So we I I built that a simple test plan
coming out of.
Coming out of the the last exercise,
so when we talk about creating a
remediation plan,
now we're dealing with how we deal with
new code modifications and how do we,
how do we want to move forward to have
you know?
How do we want to implement this?
So we want to make sure that for we have
an that we create an issue for something
that we have a strong remediation plan
for those,
for those new changes that we want to
make,
whatever that be a change the technical
debt or the like.
So we want to make sure that the the the
definition of the problem is is clear,
that any root cause analysis if it's a
defect is clear,
that there is a a proposed solution in
that issue that would guide anybody,
either a human or an A I in terms of
implementing it.
Potentially a step-by-step implementation
plan,
particularly if more than one
modification needs to be made to in order
to address this particular issue,
and then a rollback strategy,
particularly if you don't have feature
flags implemented.
You have to determine how you're going to
get back to a known good state if
something actually goes wrong with this
implementation and if it actually,
you know,
makes its way all the way into production.
And then of course you need to include
whatever test updates that need to be
made and then and you want that
Providence metadata.
So if your A I change it.
Makes changes to files or influence new
things that it it gets properly tagged
and marked so that it's you,
you know what the A I was asked to do and
what it did.
All right,
so So what we want to do now is start to
we talked about making generated issues
to make a code base Evergreen.
So anybody need any time to to finish
that exercise that we did for the
Evergreen issues and.
Raise your hand if you do.
Um.
Otherwise we'll move on and start to
implement some code.
Was that the last one?
Was I think 1 either last one or one
before that where we went through and
said you know do we want to we want to
verify that the application or or or
identify issues where the application has
problems with being Evergreen.
I I did that in our project and created a
dozen or so issues related to that.
OK.
All right,
so a couple of ways that we can we can do
this.
We can prompt a copilot to address a
technical debt. Let me kind of jump over.
Thank you here.
So if you have a if you have them as
files,
you can just reference that file in a
prompt.
And we can say something like.
Uh, let me create a new.
Chat.
Uh, take propose.
Implementation.
My dress.
Question #1.
So let's see what it produces here.
So this will give us, you know,
when we're working with a a brownfield
code base,
it's it's often a good idea to ask it
what it thinks it would like to do before
it actually executes it.
We know that in the.
Um.
The issue itself we have defined.
What that issue should be?
And um.
And it has a proposed fix,
but we're just asking here to to
reiterate what it thinks it's going to do
in order to affect that change,
one of the things that.
That this recommended fix doesn't have
that we might want to include,
and this is just a an example of where we
want to review the is that it doesn't
take any actions to remove this from the
GitHub repository,
but it does ask us to rotate that current
secret.
So that it it doesn't actually exist in
the in the new code base and therefore
can't be retrieved.
So that's one of the steps that you would
want to do if you were to to to take on
this remediation.
8.
But having said that,
it's very difficult to remove something
from git that's that's been committed.
So that that step number for the rotation
is something that is important and you
need to do.
If it actually accidentally gets
submitted to the committed to the code
base.
So it's going through doing analysis.
That will work.
It's now produced something here,
so that's security fix for the JWT
secrets. Let's go ahead and open that up.
Things want immediate remediation is to
remove the secret from the source control.
This is the code where it exists, right?
This is what it would look like if it was
modified.
Then we'll have the configuration
validation logic.
So it's now added a it's added logic here
to test for the JW secret contains this
placeholder value which will allow it to
throw an exception based upon that.
That an exception if it actually sees
that placeholder and then it would look
for the length and say that it it doesn't
conform to what its expect,
what its expectations are.
And here it's grabbing the JW secret from
the secret from the configuration file.
So at this point it's it would initialize
those user secrets for deployment.
So it would then create a user secret,
initialize that for the project and then
set that user secret to what the whatever
the the new.
Um.
It would have set that new new secret to
whatever we decided to rotate it to and
then then we could use the.
net user secret to list it so that we
actually stored it in the user secrets
and then configure production environment
variables.
That that would contain that in a secret
so that I can be use it depending upon
actually how we're deploying the
application.
Then a phase two would be moving it from
the configuration into actually a a a key
vault.
So here it's using an Azure key vault
process to actually configure that secret
in the in the key vault and then
retrieving that from the the the key
vault.
In the application as a part of the
configuration service,
so and then implementing an interface to
actually retrieve that token and then all
right here it is proposing a.
So here we're actually proposing a.
To remove the secret from the git
repository, here we see the.
An installation for a filter repo command
and we would then run a command to look
for in any app settings Jason file and
then examine that file to see if it
actually.
And the purge that.
That secret from the repository,
creating a new secret and then a a test
strategy would test to to validate.
The the work that we've done and then
implement a new security tests for that
that secret.
Some immigration tests.
Some environment configuration tests.
And then we have some quality metrics and
some success criteria and a deployment
checklist to get this out into production
and a developer guide that describes what
it is.
So this is a pretty comprehensive
implementation plan for a little bit
better than what we saw in the issue.
And so this is also a good opportunity
for us to make a change.
I don't think I'm going to execute this
one.
I think I'll pick a different one because
there's a lot of non coding steps that
need to be done to implement this one,
but it would be a good thing to attach to
the issue.
And when it comes time to actually
implement it,
you could even say here to add all of
these steps as sub issues or tasks under
the the core issue so that you could
track the implementation of those
individual steps.
So let let's take a look at something
else that might be better suitable.
That's refers to JWT.
There's no data persistence.
So it wants us to switch to a new
database provider. I think that will.
And I saw that level 2 involves.
Authorization checks for the endpoints.
And it talks about here's some problems
with the try catch.
So that might be something that we can
tackle today.
So this is issue #5.
Yes.
Issue buys.
And the weather think about that.
All right. Any questions at this point?
All right, so here what it's gonna,
it's gonna go through what we just did
and basically go in and try to plan a a a
mitigation strategy which will give us a
a sense of what the A I understands about
the the issue itself. So.
Get an interpretation of the issue and
then we'll be able to see what it
actually would attempt to do if it was
going to try to make a modification.
So while we're here,
since it's going to take some time to do
that, let's create a new session.
And I'll just say propose.
Options.
Or internally.
Future slides.
So we can see here that it's actually
it's going through not only making some
proposals on what we should consider,
but also has pros and cons of each and
looks like we have a a comparison matrix
here.
That we can use to actually, uh,
compare on the output. So let's see.
OK, let's ask it to.
Um.
Great issue.
It sure.
Once.
And.
This information.
So here we see that it's thinking about
that problem.
Same quirk that we were seeing yesterday
about the.
Problems dipping bars.
And sessions.
Um,
let's see how we're doing in other
session while we're looking for a
proposal.
It's uh.
That's a great test file. Well,
it looks like.
But we may be doing more than we asked
for here.
It looks to me like what it's done here
is actually making some modifications, so.
I think you wanna.
I'm doing these modifications since it's
something that we didn't ask for.
And then we can.
I'm gonna go back and set a new.
Toms you can go back and and say.
And.
I don't let's see proposal for issue one.
That's fine.
So let's go back and say I want the.
Propose.
And.
Commentation.
Um.
Note.
One moment.
Mhm.
The fixes.
And we'll see if that's really better.
And looks like our feature flag.
Guidance is is ready.
So it's basically put in this issue.
So this is issue 16. What's that end up?
Mhm.
Let's see here.
So it looks like it tried to create an
issue in GitHub.
Let's ask you to um.
I'm gonna go to the bottom.
Give me a link.
And then new this thing.
And that hopefully won't take too long.
Looks like we can. Here we go.
If I not up.
So here's the the general problem
statement that we want to create feature
toggles and then it gives us various
options for that.
So the first one it wants to allow us to
use is the feature feature management.
It's nice is that it's free and it's a
it's from Microsoft.
This is the recommend.
one. Umm
But it looks to me like you change the
app settings dot Jason file in order for
you to change features,
so that may not be.
What we wanted,
how we wanted to to work on it,
because we would have to do a commit to
the app settings dot Jason or modify it
in production.
So there are some limited.
There's in terms of usability,
I think it's somewhat limited.
You can use configuration based simple
flags.
This is very similar in the sense that
you're using a configuration file to do
this.
Then there's Azure app configuration.
I mentioned that which also have a
feature manager feature.
Launchdarkly is a commercial service
which is very sophisticated that allows
you to do sophisticated rollouts.
So it supports all of those Canary type
rollouts and and the and the selective
rollout to individual groups of people,
things like that.
You can use database driven flags where
you have something in the database that
gets checked that gives you like full
full dependency, full customization,
right?
But you have to have to write it all
yourself and so it's suggesting this.
As our potential implementation.
So that gives you some options in terms
of feature flags.
Let's go back and look at what we're you
know in terms of our.
Implementation for issue five.
Need some assistance here.
That's not what I was looking for.
And um.
Oh, here's issue 5.
Doesn't look like I got an implementation
plans. I must have done something wrong.
So um, maybe we should try it again.
Let's go ahead and clear the session.
OK.
In the session say.
Ready.
OK.
or issue number five.
Alright, I see this new session.
And whoever gets to know it's creating
our plan for us.
And like I said, this is a a good,
you know,
first step is to make sure that we really
understand what the what the A I is
intending to do before we actually give
it the permission to do it.
That way we we avoid anything,
any misunderstandings or any conflicts in
terms of its what it understands from its.
Instructions in order what it wants to
actually do.
That's all.
It's also a good idea to write these out
into markdown files and you can include
them as a part of your issue history so
that you documented what the actual
implementation approach is going to be,
and that way you.
You can refer back to that information in
the future.
Mm.
Alright.
Any questions on that?
So now we can basically, uh, say.
Um.
Then go ahead with the implementation.
And if we had saved this to a file at
somewhat later point on a different
machine,
we could just refer to this
implementation conversation and have it
go ahead and perform that.
That perform that implementation for us.
So while this is going to go on,
because it's likely will take some time,
let's go back to our deck.
And.
Talk about prompting copilot to address
that tactical debt, so.
Effective prompts would include the clear
description of the debt they're trying to
to affect. And we've been doing, I think,
a decent job of building that out and
building issues that contain that
description,
any constraints or architectural rules.
That aren't listed in your instruction
files should be included in the in in the
in the prompts that you give it,
what your expected outcomes are,
what required test and documentation
updates are needed,
and then with the Providence requirements
that aren't in your.
In your instruction files should be
included,
so this will give us a a faster
remediation of a consistent application
and reduced manual effort when we
actually execute the the.
Go to the products.
And we also can assign these issues to
copod. I've shown you this.
In the past,
let's go ahead and bring up copilot.
And switch to our project.
Let me bring this up here.
And I want to go to a repo.
OK.
So here at the top.
I don't see issues either. I mean,
I haven't.
I haven't possibly not turned them on.
No, it's not here.
Issues are under the general section
about halfway down.
I'm missing it.
You have to click general at the top.
Mhm.
Oh, there, thank you.
And on the right Scroll down.
OK.
We just passed it.
Right now.
That explains that.
So I I need to save this.
Does it look like it?
OK.
All right,
so let's go back and let's let's ask.
So it's working on that implementation.
What about issue #6?
Something that related to note checking,
so I'm gonna create a a new session here
and just ask it to.
Post.
Issue.
Using this I can say post issue number
six to the GitHub.
Zoom.
Let's see how I.
All right,
so it's going to create that issue.
You need a file instead.
So it's gonna create the issue without
like the labels.
All right, so it's created an issue and.
Go back to the GitHub.
I get created in the original repo.
What's that?
If you look,
you see there you can view and manage the
issue at GitHub VBMACIEEL.
No. Oh, geez.
That's not what I wanted.
I found it tried to do that with me too
and I had to reset the default repo.
How'd you do that?
I just asked Copilot.
You asked it to reset the repo.
You already asked it why it posted this
into the wrong.
I told it it needed to post to the other
URL and it determined that the default
needed to be set and then changed it for
me.
All right, post the issue to.
Uh um.
OK,
so it's gonna go ahead and try to do that.
We're still doing the implementation for
issue #5.
We can see that it's working here on.
Uh, the error structure.
And here, uh, it's.
It's uh gonna create that issue.
Let me look in in GitHub,
so hopefully we'll see that soon.
Other comments or questions on this so
far?
The goal here is that we want if we get
to put the issue into GitHub and we have
a paid subscription, we can actually ask.
Uh.
In fact,
that's probably a setting I need to check
too.
Just to make sure that I've enabled in
copilot.
The coding agent. Yeah, it's a user.
And it's right.
Then come with me.
That's all.
All right.
Well, it's asking for something here.
The Clearplay repository you provided me
the full repository name in the format of
owner repository. All right,
I can do that.
Think I can.
All right, let's see how there we go.
And so now it looks like it's going to
create the issue.
Well,
it's not giving us a link to issue #1.
Right.
So here we see our issue and it's got the
information in it.
The what the the the proposed fix would
be gonna change two new 2 files and
create a new file and if we go ahead and.
Uh, assign it to copilot.
Then what it will do is then it will take
on responsibility for implementing that.
Then we can down here we can see that
it's now.
You mentioned in this particular.
Um.
The project it's it's creating a work in
progress branch to do the implementation.
And so it will continue with that and
we'll get notifications then like we just
got one here.
That way you've created a new branch to
do that work. Let's go back to our a line.
So it's thinking up for giving it some
something to do. We see that our proposal.
We're implementing.
The Um notifications is done.
So this was for issue #5 I believe.
And we can keep that and say go ahead and.
Um.
Yeah, implements.
So you can see here that this is now
showing us that we're close to exceeding
our context window.
So it would have been a good idea to
capture this into a file and then and
then use that file as the context rather
than the line out what we currently what
we currently have in the context window.
All right, if we go back to to GitHub.
Uh, let's see here.
Looks like it's created a pull request.
Let me look at that pull request.
You'll see that it started work on this 2
minutes ago,
and here's our review session button
where we can see it co-power what it's
actually trying to do.
So this would be similar to what we would
see inside of Visual Studio code,
and we can see that it's actually
reviewing the changes.
So it's already created a generic
extension that it reduced the code
duplication and it's made that code more
maintainable.
I'm getting a piece of toast that tells
me that it's done with the refactoring.
Here we can see that it's working on
making a change.
So it's gotten some feedback from the
code review so we can see.
We we go back to the pull request.
And we we looked at this, we'll see.
Um.
That there's a modification here. Um.
It's to change 3 files.
It's got 3 commits.
Well,
I don't see anything mentioned here as a
comment to possibly the.
The code the review hasn't been done,
so maybe what we need to do here is.
market ready for review.
And if Copilot understands that,
we should be able to see a code review at
some point on the code that we've just
done.
So yeah, so here see we see copilot as.
And then it has been assigned a reviewer.
You can see here that it's actually we're
waiting for that review.
And so we'll get a notification back when
it's actually reviewed the code and we'll
see where we stand there.
So moving them back to Um.
I work here.
Here we're continuing to work on Um.
the implementation for
Uh, issue number of size.
All right.
So the notifications will tell us that
that's done. We talked about assigning.
So we're seeing how to do that.
We'll come up and review the changes when
we get notified that.
That it's done with the work that we've
assigned it.
This this could creates A repeatable
workflow. Dan, you have a question.
Yeah, maybe it was a little premature,
but basically we're using Visual Studio
to create the issues and then we go,
we go up to GitHub,
the website and then we assign it
basically to copilot and then let it do
it, let it, let it do its thing.
And then when it makes a PR and the PR is
Right.
done,
then we review it and then approve it if
we want it to.
Well, yeah,
but you we could probably improve on that
Is that basically the workflow?
workflow by taking advantage of the
GitHub CLI to assign it to, you know,
to assign the the issue to copilot.
That is one thing that we could probably
do.
To improve the workflow,
you also have the ability to review pull
requests directly inside of Visual Studio
code through the the GitHub.
See if I doesn't think I'm signed in here.
Well, anyway,
once you're signed into GitHub through
this mechanism,
you can you can then use this tool to
talk to GitHub and actually do the pull
requests from there if you wanted.
So those are different ways that you can
accomplish this in terms of your your
workflow.
OK, that I think that GitHub.
I don't see it in my Visual Studio code.
That must be an extension then is that.
No, it's. Oh, you don't see it. Yeah,
it is an extension.
So.
That they get a pull request extension.
Yes.
OK.
All right,
so it's done some work here that we
haven't reviewed.
So we've marked the pull request as I
want to pull this is ready to review and
then I reviewed requested to automatic
review settings so it determined that it
needed to do that. Here we can view the.
The session that it used that it went
into in terms of reviewing the pull
request, what it did.
Right. And then, um.
Good.
Where is the setting to do the automatic
review of the pull request? Is that?
Mm.
Uh, that's under settings under copilot.
There's settings for that.
Mhm.
Under code would be right.
Yeah, right here.
Uh, I see.
All right,
So what it looks like here is it wants to.
On a PowerShell commands.
All right,
so it thinks it's done the job with issue
#6.
Let's go back to the the pull request
that we were looking at.
And just go back a little bit further
down we were.
It looks like it changed the title of the
pull requests.
And um.
It's now assigned me as a reviewer so
that I can review the the work as well.
It's finished that work and it has a
review code review overview.
And it doesn't uh.
Oh um.
Review changes.
The only suggestion it's making is to use
a copilot instructions.
So it's telling us here to oh,
here's an extension to querable.
It's actually it's suggesting that we
would modify our.
Um.
So that this basically currently requires
a non null error message,
which means that we every call still has
to pass the same boulder crate string
consider making error message optional
and so so it's it's just sort of
modification.
If we like that we can go ahead and
commit that change.
And that will actually make a
modification to the code to do what it's
suggesting that we do and we can resolve
that conversation.
It's also here proposing.
Exclamation mark change here,
so it lets it change the code for that
and it wants to modify a method that
contains a name that contains a typo.
Uh.
And here's a exceptions appear to be
unused in this file after switching to
this,
so it wants to remove this using
statement.
And that the this also using data it
wants to remove from the other file and
then it allows us to to.
To go ahead and and merge that in.
If we if we choose,
we can either choose to make these
modifications which is up to us and and
then we can then merge that pull request
back into the main branch.
So this is the the workflow here.
So the idea is that you know the the code
review is great because it modifies that
pull request and adds comments for things
and it looks like you know that it was
able to make suggestions for improvements
that it can make for all of these issues.
So it would be just a.
The simple.
Chain simple activity to go ahead and say.
Commit that suggestion.
And then?
Move on and commit.
Well,
here we can say just all the all the all
the changes and then we'll go ahead and
do that.
So when it's done,
when we should select that copilot,
apply changes based on the comments in
this thread.
And so this is something that's also nice
to be aware of that any app con copilot
in a comment will allow you to instruct
the copilot to do something on your
behalf.
And here it's basically applying these
changes for this particular review
comment.
And so this will queue up those changes
and we should then see that it's going to
implement those modifications.
All right. Any questions on this so far?
So then why don't we spend some time
going through our own list of issues and
let's see if we can create some
implementation,
proposed implementation fixes for those
issues and then.
Uh, implement those fixes.
Go ahead and raise your hand so I know
when you're finished and we've got about
20 minutes to to work on this.
Yeah.
I have a question so on on I I did this
earlier and so one of the pull requests
there is failing checks and it looks like
it says it's ready for review.
So can I just add a comment to tell it to
fix the?
Fix the failing checks or?
Yeah, yeah, you can.
Pilot.
Copilot go ahead and you know address
that particular problem.
You may need to copy some text into the.
Into the comment if it's not easily
referable.
I think comments have a link like we were
saying that you can capture and use that
and to to point copilot to what you
actually want it to do.
It really depends on.
You know,
if copilot isn't actually proposing a a a
a fix for a change or for something that
it's,
then it may need more information in
order to be able to actually execute.
So it's Copilot has now finished the work
that I did there.
Mhm.
So I'm getting notifications for all the
work that's done.
And you know,
go ahead and raise your hand if you're
still working on it so that I can see
when everybody's completed.
Mm.
Oh.
Is the voice still working?
Yep, still working.
All right.
I have a question. So it's saying um.
Pending view,
it's one workflow awaiting approval.
I guess I have to approve workflows to
run. This is on a pull request.
Mhm.
You're getting this in GitHub or you're
seeing this in Visual Studio?
It's in GitHub I can show you.
Um.
And I'll show you.
Put in the chat a screenshot.
Thank you.
I guess I can approve it,
but it's happened on a couple of them.
I guess I was wondering whether there's.
The setting or something or do they
really want us to approve everything?
Um.
Yeah, I haven't. I haven't seen that,
but um.
You can always click the link that tells
to meet more,
but and it might give you some guidance
in terms of what it's actually trying to
do, because that's what I don't see is.
Um.
Yeah,
I guess here I guess I can set it to
approved.
OK.
I tagged copilot in my my PR same way
that you did, John,
but it does not seem to be taking any
sort of action.
Mhm.
I'm guessing that that's an
organizational thing.
Yeah, it could be.
If you're using the free plan,
it's probably not available to you.
Preplan.
It's probably not available to you.
I think I'm on the free one, but uh,
it might not be the enterprise.
I shouldn't. I don't have any.
I'm just running Pro Plus and I'm able to
do this.
So there must be something else that's
that we're that you're missing that
that's preventing that.
I think with enterprise your repo has to
be in the enterprise org.
Right.
Or compile it to work for code review.
The enterprise to for compiles work with
code review, that's what you said.
The repo should be in the enterprise like
org.
Right.
So they could get how about the
4.
enterprise implementation that they that
they put everybody that has an enterprise
license into.
So your repos have to go into that.
.
Into that.
I'm sure it has a different URL than just
github.com.
And I'd use that to further isolate into
implants.
Uh,
additional features other than what you
get in the standard version.
Mm.
So it looks like these are all done.
Anybody else still working?
Looks like we're just about done for the
day.
All right, good. So what I'm working on,
I'll show you in the morning is that is a
multi implementation comparison and how
to go about doing that.
I'm a little messed up here that I got to
clean up my workspace to be able to do
that.
But that's a a great technique for
evaluating the pros and cons of different
implementations,
and that way you can use that to find
different solutions to problems and and
then evaluate the pros and cons of each.
And then we'll move on into the
Greenfield part of the course. All right.
So that's it for today.
If you have any questions about this
exercise,
we can pick them up in the morning.
So have a good day. Good evening.
Thank you. Night.
Thanks. Take care.
Thank you.
Thanks.
Thank you. Good evening.
Thank you.
Right.